tmbank.com.au 2014-02-13

# Privacy Information Statement

> Member Privacy Statement   
> Non-Member Privacy Statement

## Member Privacy statement

Teachers Mutual Bank has always respected members' rights to Privacy. It is fundamental to the way we do business and reflects the trust members have placed in us in providing them with financial services.

#### Our commitment

In handling your personal information, Teachers Mutual Bank is committed to complying with the Privacy Act 1988, the National Privacy Principles and the Customer Owned Banking Code of Practice.  

#### Why do we require your personal information?

We collect personal information from you when you apply for membership, when you apply to use our products and services or when you otherwise provide us with information. If it is necessary for us to collect information about you from a third party, we will inform you wherever possible. This information enables us to provide:

  * membership benefits to you 
  * the products and services you require, and 
  * information about products and services available to you from Teachers Mutual Bank and associated businesses including information about special offers, discounts and competitions. 

In line with new technology, we are continually improving the security of the information we collect.

We do not generally collect information that is 'sensitive personal information' as defined by the Privacy Act 1988. However, we may on occasion collect information relating to your health and trade union membership. Such information will only be collected from you and will only be used for the purpose for which it was collected.

#### Providing your personal information to other organisations

Personal information is treated as confidential and is used by us for the purpose for which it was collected or for a related purpose. Related purposes may include:  

  * our own market analysis and product development 
  * informing you about new products or services, and 
  * detecting and preventing fraud and other criminal activity. 

In providing products and services to you it may be necessary for us to provide your personal information to other organisations with whom we conduct business. We do not disclose sensitive personal information to third parties without your permission or instruction.

Other organisations include related entities, solicitors and legal advisors, accountants and auditors, printers and mailing services, insurers, collection agents, conveyancers, valuers, Cuscal Limited, (our national credit union body) and government agencies which regulate our products and services. These other organisations are bound by confidentiality and non-disclosure agreements which prohibit them from using your information for any other purpose.

Your personal information is only provided to those entities to the extent necessary to enable us to provide our products and services to you and to the extent required by law. Examples include tax file numbers, Medicare numbers and Pension numbers.

#### Information about you from third parties

We may need to source information about you from a third party; for example, a credit reporting agency, an insurer, another financial institution and foreign currency suppliers. Wherever possible this will be done with your authorisation or where this is not possible we will inform you when such information is collected.  

#### Receiving marketing information

We may provide you with information from time to time about new products and services available to you from Teachers Mutual Bank, or other businesses with whom we have a relationship. Your consent to our providing this information to you will be implied unless you notify us that you do not wish to receive this information. You may do this by contacting us and advising that you do not wish to receive marketing information.  

#### Information we are required to send to you

Under our Constitution, which members have adopted and only they can agree to amend, we are required to provide you with certain information. This information includes notices of meetings, elections and any proposed changes to the Constitution. As we are legally obliged to provide this detail to you it is not possible for you to be excluded from receiving it. 

We are also legally bound to provide statements to members and notices of variation to account or contract terms. We therefore include Chalkboard and Edvest newsletters with members' statements, which contain important information relating to members' accounts and current services that members would not otherwise receive.

#### What if you do not wish to provide us with information?

In order to provide products and services to you we require information about you. If you do not provide us with all of the information we require we may be unable to provide products or services to you. If you do not provide us with your Tax File Number there may also be taxation implications for you.  

#### Your rights to access information

Under the Privacy Act you have the right to access personal information we hold about you. Where we incur a cost in copying and retrieving documents and files, this cost may be passed on to you. If the information is incorrect, you have the right to require us to amend the information.

We rely on the accuracy of the information you provide to us. If you believe or know that information we hold about you is incorrect, out of date or incomplete, call **13 12 21** and we will make all reasonable efforts to correct the information.

#### Further information

Should you require further information about our Privacy Information Statement or access to your personal information call **13 12 21  **8am to 7pm, weekdays and 9am to 3pm, Saturday.

## Non-Member Privacy Statement

Teachers Mutual Bank has always respected customers’ rights to Privacy. It is fundamental to the way we do business and reflects the trust customers have placed in us in providing them with financial services.   

#### Our commitment

In handling your personal information, Teachers Mutual Bank is committed to complying with the Privacy Act 1988, the National   
Privacy Principles and the Customer Owned Banking Code of Practice. 

#### Why do we require your personal information?

We collect personal information from you when you apply to use our product or when you otherwise provide us with information. If it is necessary for us to collect information about you from a third party, we will inform you wherever possible. This information enables us to provide:   

  * the product you require, and 
  * information about the product available to you from Teachers Mutual Bank and associated businesses including information about special offers, discounts and competitions. 

In line with new technology, we are continually improving the security of the information we collect. We do not generally collect information that is ‘sensitive personal information’ as defined by the Privacy Act 1988. Such information will only be collected from you and will only be used for the purpose for which it was collected. 

#### Providing your personal information to other organisations

Personal information is treated as confidential within Teachers Mutual Bank and is used by us for the purpose for which it was collected or for a related purpose. Related purposes may include: 

  * our own market analysis and product development; 
  * informing you about new products or services; and 
  * detecting and preventing fraud and other criminal activity. 

In providing a product to you it may be necessary for us to provide your personal information to other organisations with whom we conduct business. We do not disclose sensitive personal information to third parties without your permission or instruction. 

Other organisations include related entities, solicitors and legal advisors, accountants and auditors, printers, mailing services, insurers, collection agents, conveyancers, valuers, Mutual Bank Services Corporation Australia Ltd, (our national mutual bank body) and government agencies which regulate our products and services. 

These other organisations are bound by confidentiality and nondisclosure agreements which prohibit them from using your information for any other purpose. Your personal information is only provided to those entities to the extent necessary to enable us to provide our product to you and to the extent required by law. Examples include tax file numbers, Medicare numbers and Pension numbers. 

#### Information about you from third parties

We may need to source information about you from a third party; for example, a credit reporting agency, an insurer, another financial institution and foreign currency suppliers. Wherever possible this will be done with your authorisation or where this is not possible we will inform you when such information is collected. 

#### Receiving marketing information

We may provide you with information from time to time about new products and services available to you from Teachers Mutual Bank, or other businesses with whom we have a relationship. Your consent to our providing this information to you will be implied unless you notify us that you do not wish to receive this information. You may do this by contacting us and advising that you do not wish to receive marketing information. 

#### Information we are required to send to you

We are legally bound to provide statements to customers and notices of variation to account or contract terms. 

#### What if you do not wish to provide us with information

In order to provide our product to you we require information about you. If you do not provide us with all of the information we require we may be unable to provide products or services to you. If you do not provide us with your Tax File Number there may also be taxation implications for you. 

#### Your rights to access information

Under the Privacy Act you have the right to access personal information we hold about you. Where we incur a cost in copying and retrieving documents and files, this cost may be passed on to you. If the information is incorrect, you have the right to require us to amend the information. We rely on the accuracy of the information you provide to us. If you believe or know that information we hold about you is incorrect, out of date or incomplete, please contact us on **13 12 21** and we will make all reasonable efforts to correct the information. 

#### Further information

If you require further information about our Privacy Policy or access to your personal information, please contact **13 12 21** 8am to 7pm, weekdays or 9am to 3pm, Saturday.
